lostpassword.com 2019-03-19

# Privacy

The following Passware Privacy Policy will be effective starting May 25, 2018.

Below is the description of how we collect, use, and handle your personal information when you use our website, software, and services.

## What & Why

We collect and use the following information to provide, improve, and protect our services:

### Account information

We collect—and associate with your account—the information you provide to us when you make a purchase for our software (e.g., your full name, email address, billing address, phone number, etc.).

### Usage information

We collect information related to how you use the software, including actions you take when using our software (like password recovery tasks) and license details (product key used), only if you agree to take part in our Customer Experience Improvement Program (CEIP).

We use this information to improve our software, develop new features, and protect Passware users.

### Device information

We also collect information from and about the devices you use to access the Services. This includes things like IP addresses, system language, the type of browser and device you use, and the version of our software. Your devices (depending on their settings) may also transmit location information to our server.

### Crash reports and diagnostic information

We may also collect reports of app crashes and significant errors generated by our software so that we can identify and fix software bugs as soon as possible. These reports may include things like file names, hardware model, process information, app and device information, etc. To collect this information, we ask for your consent in advance.

### Cookies and other technologies

We use technologies like cookies to provide, improve, protect, and promote our software. For example, cookies help us with understanding how you are interacting with our website and improving them based on that information. A "cookie" is a small data file stored by your web browser on your computer's hard drive. Passware Inc. collects cookies on our website to capture information about page visits. This information is anonymous, and we only use it internally to gauge page popularity, analyze traffic patterns on our site, and guide development of other improvements to our site. You can set your browser to not accept cookies, but this may limit your ability to use the website.

### Marketing

We give users the option to use some of our products free of charge or with a discount. We allow you to register to receive periodic email correspondence from us through our newsletter. The information we collect for this purpose is your email address, first name, and last name. Users who receive these marketing materials can opt out at any time. If you do not want to receive marketing materials from us, simply click the ‘unsubscribe’ link in any email.

### Bases for processing your data

We collect and use the personal data described above in order to provide you with software and service in a reliable and secure manner. We also collect and use personal data for our legitimate business needs. To the extent we process your personal data for other purposes, we ask for your consent in advance or require that our partners obtain such consent.

## With Whom

We may share information as discussed below, but we won’t sell it to advertisers or other third parties.

### Others working for and with Passware

Passware uses certain trusted third parties (for example, providers of customer support and IT services) to help us provide, improve, protect, and promote our software and service. These third parties will access your information only to perform tasks on our behalf in compliance with this Privacy Policy, and we’ll remain responsible for their handling of your information per our instructions.

### Law & Order and the Public Interest

We may disclose your information to third parties if we determine that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to (a) comply with any applicable law, regulation, legal process, or appropriate government request; (b) protect any person from death or serious bodily injury; (c) prevent fraud or abuse of Passware or our users; (d) protect Passware’s rights, property, safety, or interest; or (e) perform a task carried out in the public interest.

## How

### Security

We are dedicated to keeping your information secure and testing for vulnerabilities. We also continue to work on features to keep your information safe in addition to things like file encryption.

### User Controls

You can access, amend, download, and delete your personal information by sending the corresponding request to Passware Support at [csupport@passware.com](mailto:csupport@passware.com).

## Where

### Around the world

To provide you with the software and service, we may store, process, and transmit information in the United States, EU, and locations around the world—including those outside your country. Information may also be stored locally on the devices you use to access the services.

## Changes

If we are involved in a reorganization, merger, acquisition, or sale of our assets, your information may be transferred as part of that deal. We will notify you (for example, via a message to the email address associated with your account) of any such deal and outline your choices in that event.

We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time and will post the most current version on our website. If a revision meaningfully reduces your rights, we will notify you.

## Your Right to Control and Access Your Information

You have control over your personal information and how it is collected, used, and shared. For example, you have a right to: **Erase or delete all or some of your SMS Subscription account data**. You can delete your account information by contacting Passware Support. **Change or correct personal data**. You can manage your account and the content contained in it, as well as edit some of your personal data by contacting Passware Support.

## Contact

Have questions or concerns about Passware, our software, and privacy? Contact our Support representative at [csupport@passware.com](mailto:csupport@passware.com).

**Last Updated:** 5/25/2018
